{
    "id": "194c9f6ff8994af6871cad3c091c70e7",
    "title": "English Vocabulary Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She takes a wayward delight in disagreeing with everyone. The word wayward can be replaced by …………………",
            "description": "Perverse can mean wayward.",
            "answers": [
                "perturbed",
                "nonplussed",
                "perverse"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The teacher was perturbed by the student’s lack of interest.  The word perturbed can be replaced by .................................",
            "description": "Disconcerted can mean perturbed.",
            "answers": [
                "discarded",
                "nonplussed",
                "disconcerted"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He has a perverted sense of right and wrong. The word perverted can be replaced by ……………………",
            "description": "Distorted can mean perverted.",
            "answers": [
                "discomfited",
                "dissuaded",
                "distorted"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She stood there, frozen with fear. The word frozen can be replaced by …………………..",
            "description": "Petrified can mean frozen.",
            "answers": [
                "pestered",
                "putrefied",
                "petrified"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "When he doesn’t get his way, he can be quite peevish. Here the word peevish can be replaced by ……………………",
            "description": "Petulant can mean peevish.",
            "answers": [
                "meek",
                "pervasive",
                "petulant"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Should parents be strict or indulgent? Here the word indulgent can be replaced by ……………………..",
            "description": "Permissive can mean indulgent. ",
            "answers": [
                "permissive",
                "pervasive",
                "nonchalant"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I am tired of his perpetual nagging. Here the word perpetual can be replaced by ……………………",
            "description": "Perpetual means incessant.",
            "answers": [
                "recurring",
                "incessant",
                "intermittent"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is much too assertive to cooperate with others. Here the word assertive can be replaced by ………………………",
            "description": "Peremptory means assertive ",
            "answers": [
                "perilous",
                "preposterous",
                "peremptory"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The fat boy had a preference for rich desserts. Here the word preference can be replaced by ……………………….",
            "description": "Penchant means preference.",
            "answers": [
                "penchant",
                "petulance",
                "niche"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When you ask him a question, you get a pedantic answer. Here the word pedantic can be replaced by …………………..",
            "description": "The words pedantic and didactic can mean pompous.",
            "answers": [
                "delectable",
                "diligent",
                "didactic"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The poodle had an impressive lineage. Here the word lineage can be replaced by ……………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "generation",
                "class",
                "pedigree"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The idea of a chaperon for a dating couple is passé. Here the word passé can be replaced by …………………….",
            "description": "If something is passe, it is obsolete or outdated. ",
            "answers": [
                "modern",
                "revolutionary",
                "obsolete"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}